So now that everything is in order, we can move to the next stage, which is building up the mechanics
of the game.
Now normally we would start with our main player sprite because after all, it is our main player.
However, before this there is something even more important which is our road because it makes it actually
look like we're driving.
Now you may be wondering how do we make it look like our car is moving forward?
Well, this is where the art of illusion comes in.
You see, in our game, we want to give the player a sense of continuous motion, as if they're driving
down an endless road.
To achieve this, we need to pay close attention to the alignment of our road lines and also other visual
elements.
It's sort of like a magician's trick.
If we do it just right, we can create an illusion that feels real and seamless to the plan.
Now imagine you're watching a well executed magic trick.
Your eyes are glued to the magician's hands as they effortlessly create the illusion of reality.
That's what we want to do with our game.
We want our players to be so captivated by the seamless loop that they don't notice the trick behind
it.
And to create this illusion of motion, we'll be using stretched backgrounds and clever manipulation
of the x and Y positions.
The key here is to ensure that our road lines and other elements aligned perfectly, so the loop appears
smooth and continuous.
But why is this precision so important, you may ask?
Well, the slightest misalignment can break the illusion, making the game feel less immersive and enjoyable.
Remember, our goal is to captivate the player and make them feel like they are truly driving down an
endless road.
And this part might get quite tricky.
So if you find this stage too challenging, remember you can always download the full project asset
with the completed sprites.
However, the stage will definitely increase your skill in costume design and game development.
Right.
Let's get this endless loop underway.
So if we go to our road sprite and then costumes, you can see we have, well, just these lines.
And right now our road lines are the exact size of our screen.
So if they were to come down even the slightest bit, the illusion would be broken.
So what we want is to extend the road past these borders here.
If you try to do this now, you will see it just vanishes into the abyss.
So the first thing we need to do is convert it into a vector, which now, as you can see, gives us
a load more options, including bringing the image off the screen.
So to extend this image, what we can do is bring it down.
And remember we can use the arrow keys just so we have more control.
And also if you hold shift while clicking you can see it moves a lot further.
Anyway.
Right here.
Looks about good.
So now we can copy this and then paste it.
And before moving it up we can make sure it is exactly aligned horizontally.
Now again using the arrow keys we can bring it up.
Now the final step is to make sure these gaps are the same.
So here just carefully look at the road as you slowly move it up to make sure these two gaps are the
same.
And that looks pretty good.
Again, this might take a bit of trial and error to get it perfect.
But with that, our costume is ready.
We can now move to the exciting part animating it, which we'll do in the next lesson.